Kedar Krishnan

2 Lewis Younie Road, Huapai - Kumeu, Auckland 0810

E: kedar.krishnan@gmail.com M: 027 431 5111

SUMMARY

I am a full stack developer that has worked in the diverse environment including Fortune 500 technology company JP Morgan Chase. Have a large toolbox of skills and technologies that can be used to work on a variety of projects and add value, e.g. build the web from backend to frontend, develop restful web services, deploy the web infrastructure in the cloud.

SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES (with years of experience)

Programming Languages: Java (12+ years) • JavaScript (2+

years) • VB (1+ year) • C++ (0.5 year)

Web Development: HTML5 (2+ years) • CSS (2+ years) • NodeJs

(0.25 years) • JSP (2+ years)

Frameworks: Spring (8 + years) • Hibernate (1+ year) • JQuery

 $(1+ year) \cdot AngularJS (0.5+ years) \cdot D3 charts (0.5+ years) \cdot$

Bootstrap (1 + years) • Mule (0.5+ years) • Kubernetes (0.5+

years) • Kibana (0.5+ years) • ELK (0.5+ years)

Messaging: Kafka (1 + years), Kafka-connect (1 + years)

Database: MySQL (3+ years) • Oracle (10+ years)

Reporting: BIRT (6+ years) • Cognos (0.5+ years) • Jasper (1+

year)

Cloud: Bluemix (0.5+ years) • AWS (1+ years)

Version Control: Git (2+ years) • SVN (4+ years)

CICD: Jenkins (2+ years), Terraform (1+ years), Docker (0.5+

years), Kubernetes (0.5+ years)

Design: Photoshop, Illustrator, Photography (Elementary)

Development Methodology: Agile SCRUM (2.5+ years) • TDD

(0.5+ years) • Waterfall (9+ years)

OPEN SOURCE AND COMMUNITY

APB: A medical emergency alert system with a Web administration and a mobile application created using Android Java, spring web services, AngularJS and MYSQL.

InfoGraph.js: A JavaScript charting module, used for displaying profile skills info-graph on the web page.

Indian-states-cities: A NodeJS module for getting states and cities of India based on criteria.

GovHack: Participated in GovHack 2016 Auckland. Awarded "Voted best embodiment of the Sprint of GovHack for amazing teamwork" http://2016.hackerspace.govhack.org/content/ptp

Web page: http://kedarkrishnan.github.io/

Github page: https://github.com/kedarkrishnan

WORK EXPERIENCE

Developer University of Auckland (NZ); Feb 2018 – Present

Skills used: Java, Spring-Boot, Mule, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Kong API gateway,

Role overview:

- MuleSoft and Spring Boot API Development
- RAML and Swagger based APIs design and implementation
- Kafka, MuleSoft and Java based Integrations of different applications
- Kubernetes & Docker orchestration platform deployment / build / start scripts, services, config-maps and secrets management
- Elastic, Kibana, Logstash logging (ELK) stack
- Angular 6 UI development for internal application (Athena)
- AWS deployment pipeline implementation using terraform

Lead Developer, Internship Avatar International (NZ); Dec 2016 – Jun 2017

Skills used: Java, Spring-Boot, Hibernate, Bootstrap, AngularJS, MySQL

Role overview:

- Develop backend restful API using Spring-Boot
- Design bootstrap responsive website.
- Develop frontend using Work with AngularJS(1.5)

 Coordinate with other BAs and Developers in designing business logic.

Associate – Developer JP MORGAN; Oct 2008 – Jun 2016

Skills used: Java, Spring, Hibernate, BIRT, SCRUM, Git, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery

Role overview:

- Creating Spring Restful web service endpoints (JSON) to make resources available to frontend
- Writing and reviewing test cases using JUnit and spring test context framework
- Re-designing existing Restful API service to support different response output
- Development of internal inventory management system using Spring MVC, CSS and JQuery
- Building interactive functionality on reports using Bootstrap, Javascript and Jquery so that users can change the structure of the reports at runtime.
- Re-designing frontend for administration application using CSS, Javascript and Bootstrap
- Working in two week agile sprints which involved desk check to the testers and demo to the stakeholders
- Responsible for addressing security risks for the projects
- Work closely with US Chicago counter parts for coordinating delivery of the project tasks
- Continuous integration environment management and coordination with the infra structure team for different DEV, QA, IST environments for different releases

Analyst Programmer SYNTEL; Jan 2006 – Oct 2008

Skills used: Java, JSP, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, JQuery

Role overview:

- Designing and development of a customizable portal for displaying dashboard for Syntel's Center of Excellence team using Java, JSP, CSS, Javascript and HTML
- Work on projects from different clients like State Street, Wells Fargo for creating their reporting frontend using Java, JSP.

• Working with clients for requirement gathering, creating technical analysis document (TAD).

Developer SEEINFOBIZ; Nov 2003 – Jan 2006

Skills used: Java, JSP, CSS, HTML, JavaScript

Role overview:

• Designing and developing a customer-billing system for Telecommunication Company using Java, JSP and CSS, HTML.

EDUCATION QUALIFICATION

Graduate Diploma in Computing

Unitec - Auckland, New Zealand; 2016 - July 2017

Bachelor of Engineering

Mumbai University; 1997 - 2001

OTHER

Work Eligibility: Legally entitled to work in New Zealand